GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
I'm assuming the
captaincy of Gotham Central.
HARVEY: You just better hope
you can pay up when your bill's due.
And it'll come due.
ALFRED: Let me know
how I can help you.
BRUCE: Stop trying
to be my father.
(GROANS)
ALFRED: Master
Bruce, I'm so sorry.
Alfred, you're fired.
This is your turf now.
NYGMA: You're new
leader of The Narrows.
I am in control!
(LAUGHS WICKEDLY)
You're in love with
Lee Thompkins,
you pathetic loser.
Shut up!
Where are they?
MAN: That's powerful stuff.
It can get in your DNA.
TABITHA: You're gonna
remember me, Butch...
(CLANGS)
I'm sorry.
I tried.
BUTCH: What the
hell happened to me?
(GUNSHOT)
GORDON: That was you.
You sent this
monster to my city?
HARVEY: I heard you got the Pyg.
Turned out well.
You didn't even need me...
They, uh, believe in
you. Don't let them down.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RECORD)
WOMAN: How can I
help you, Captain Gordon?
I assure you this is a
respectable establishment.
Relax, I'm not here
to shut you down.
I'm looking for someone.
We are trusted
for our discretion.
Mmm-hmm.
Was he here?
Who did he spend the night with?
He specifically requested
Tallulah and Pip.
That's him.
That's Bullock.
If he comes back,
please tell him to call me.
(TRAIN PASSING)
(UNLOCKING DOOR)
It was an old
Chinese guy's place,
filled with rare
drugs and stuff.
He split town.
Place is empty now.
Where are the drugs?
You said there'd be drugs.
Holy crap.
What the...
Don't touch it, dude.
(SQUELCHING)
MAN: You just woke it up.
Hey, Tiffany, who's
the stiff at the counter?
New customer, nice guy, polite.
Leave him alone, okay?
Hey, new guy?
Do I know you?
No, mate. Most definitely not.
Not from around here, huh?
And what gave you that idea?
Here, miss. Thank you very much.
Keep the change.
That stiff's shoes are
worth more than my car.
(DOOR OPENS)
LEE: I understand
times are tough.
I understand you
need to make a living.
But it's time to stop
punishing each other
for the situation the
city has put you in.
Instead of stealing from
those hurting as much as you,
this community needs to
start protecting one another.
We do what we do to survive!
ALL: Yeah.
And is that all you
want, all of you?
Just to survive every
day, one day at a time?
Listen, Doc, down here,
it's every man for himself!
That's the way it's always been!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
How many of you have kids?
I've been running
a clinic down here
for the last nine months,
and I have been treating
your kids for things like TB,
hepatitis, pertussis, pneumonia.
Diseases that don't
belong in a modern city.
But there are no functioning
hospitals down here,
and doctors are
too afraid to visit.
You're not stealing
from the rich,
- you're stealing from each other.
- (TICKING)
You are fighting each other,
and you are living in a prison
of your own construction.
MAN: Well, hello,
beautiful. What's your name?
Ivy.
My name was Ivy.
Well, Ivy,
what's a nice girl like you
doing in a place like this?
(SCREAMS)
(MUFFLED GROANS)
(SHUSHING)
Well, that's a hell of a thing.
Let's go!
(DOOR CLOSES)
Extraordinary.
MAN: Hey.
Little Lord Fuddy-duddy.
It's Fauntleroy.
What?
Little Lord Fauntleroy by
Frances Hodgson Burnett.
A tad saccharin for my tastes...
Shut up. Wallet, watch, jewelry.
Absolutely not.
I mean, you're a big man,
but you're out of shape.
And what, you're
three beers in already?
GORDON: That's enough!
Get out of here.
Not who I was
expecting to see here.
Likewise.
GORDON: Is Bruce with you?
No.
What are you doing here?
Well, it's not too
bad down here really.
I mean, you can
rent a lovely space
for next to nothing,
if you move around
and you're patient.
You live here?
Nearby.
It's a long story.
Give me the chance
to prove to you
(MAN COUGHS)
that I can turn The
Narrows into a place
where you don't have to
steal from one another to live.
Yes.
CROWD: Yeah.
Yeah.
(CROWD CLAPPING AND CHEERING)
(TICKING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(ALL COUGHING)
All right.
Go, come on.
Go, go, go.
Go. Go.
Everyone, move
away from the building!
(ALARM BLARING)
- (SIREN WAILING)
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
GORDON: There's
your mom. Go ahead.
Mommy!
That's the last one.
- Building's clear.
- Okay.
- (MAN COUGHING)
- Oxygen. Please.
OFFICER: Over here, over here.
Listen up. We need
to set up a perimeter,
and start interviewing
witnesses. Let's go.
ALFRED: Well, they seem on it.
Appears like you turned around
the GCPD, Captain Gordon.
LUCIUS: Gordon!
Quite a mess. Thought
you might need help.
Thank you. We need to
find the source of the blast.
Alfred, I do want
to talk to you,
but I have to
deal with this first.
- You have my number. Call me.
- All right.
Let's go.
GORDON: I'll ask you one
more time. Why were you here?
It was a wine and cheese
mixer. (CHUCKLES)
Laugh all you want.
They were trying to kill you.
This is The Narrows, bud.
That's every day around here.
MAN: Yeah, just another
beautiful day in The Narrows, Cap.
LUCIUS: Gordon.
Get him out of here.
What you got?
Well, it seems like a
piece of a toy plane.
And, yet, if I'm not mistaken,
it's covered in plastic
explosive residue.
There's also the remnants of
what seems like a trigger wire.
Whoever built it,
takes pride in their work
and has considerable talent,
historical knowledge
even. Look at the detail.
Pretty elaborate.
I can think of easier ways
to kill a room full of
criminals than with a toy plane.
Perhaps, it was intended
to fly to someone specific
and not destroy the whole room.
Like an assassination attempt?
If so, who was the target?
Whoever this was, needs
to be made an example of.
I mean, can't they tell
you were trying to help.
- Maybe it wasn't one of them.
- Oh, of course, it was.
I just think that maybe the
best thing for The Narrows
is to burn it to the
ground! Start over.
Well, that would certainly
suit everyone, wouldn't it?
I'm just saying someone
tried to blow you to bits,
and I bet they're
gonna try it again!
So I'm going to find
them, and when I do,
Grundy's going to pull
them apart, limb by limb!
Isn't that right, big fella?
Hey, Grundy?
You okay?
Okay.
(NYGMA SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
- (SLASHES)
- (SCREAMS)
My name is Butch.
(GUNSHOT)
Butch Gilzean.
MAN: There he is.
(APPLAUDING)
That was so brave, sir.
It's Alfred, please.
It's the good stuff.
Our manager hides
it in his drawer.
ALFRED: Thank you.
On the house.
(SIGHS)
What you did out there,
running into a
burning building...
Well, I wouldn't have done it.
No hard feelings, eh?
No.
Good man.
Thanks.
- Cheers.
Cheers.
ALFRED: What happened there?
I fell. No big deal.
There are a few
places in the city
that collect and
sell antique toys,
but only this one also
manufactures its own.
(BELLS CHIMING)
(TOYS WHIRRING)
(TOY CACKLING)
Um...
Can I help you, gentlemen?
LUCIUS: Yes.
We were wondering if
you recognized this plane?
One of yours?
Where did you find it?
Yours or not?
It's a pine and lead
1944 Mustang replica.
We have these, yes,
but it's been altered.
To carry a bomb, yeah.
GORDON: How many
people work here?
Just me and my father.
GORDON: And where is he?
Upstairs.
Go get him.
LUCIUS: Got a hunch
you'd like to share?
No.
Just a bad feeling.
Of course, I'd happily be wrong.
(SIGHS) Who buys these things?
GORDON: I'm not
sure any of it is for sale.
I don't see price
tags on anything.
LUCIUS: Any word from Harvey?
Not yet.
Think he'll return to the GCPD?
To be honest, I'm not sure.
LUCIUS: Um...
- Gordon...
- Get down!
(GUNSHOTS)
ROBOT: Seek and destroy.
Seek and destroy.
- Seek and destroy.
- (BEEPING)
You've got to be kidding me.
(BOMB BEEPS)
Wait, wait. No, no, wait,
wait, wait. Come on, he's...
He's my father.
I can't let you hurt him.
I swear to God, I had no
idea what my father was up to.
There's a machine gun built into
the wooden hand of
this nutcracker here.
Excuse me if I find
that hard to believe.
I didn't know, okay?
My father, he hates
to be disturbed.
He also built a bomb that almost
blew up a building this morning.
We need to know why.
- Who was the target?
- I don't know.
LUCIUS: Has anyone
suspicious been here recently,
asking for specialty toys?
No one comes in here,
this is just his workshop.
He mostly works at night.
See, he boxes the
things he makes and
ships them.
What?
Like, three days ago,
I thought I heard him talking
to someone behind his door.
His voice was low, like he
didn't want me to hear him.
Did you hear a name?
I heard my father
repeat something,
like he was confirming a name.
He said, "The Doc."
The Doc? Who's that?
I have no idea.
(SIREN WAILING)
Hey, can you deal with this?
I'm gonna talk to somebody
who might know who the Doc is.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
This place is killing you.
- (HONKING)
- WOMAN: Honey, the taxi is here.
MAN: Let's go.
WOMAN: If we are late...
MAN: We need to
pack the other stuff...
WOMAN: Okay. Of
course it's my fault.
MAN: You only need,
like, five pairs of shoes.
WOMAN: Come on.
Let's go. Let's go.
- (CAR DOOR CLOSES)
- (ENGINE STARTS)
(TV REMOTE CLICKS)
REPORTER ON TV: the truck
overturned spilling its load of gasoline
into Gotham's Nature Park.
The GCPD is warning all
citizens to remain clear of the...
MAN ON TV: causing gas
to leak into the water supply
which then ignited,
setting fire to the
resident's kitchen
which set off a 24-acre blaze.
Wayne Enterprises can't...
WOMAN ON TV: Now, there's no
reason to ever be alone in this city again.
The Sirens Club is
back, with a passion.
Ladies drink for
free whilst men don't.
You'll like it. It's nice.
I know you.
All of you.
And I'm pretty sure I hated you.
(WOMAN LAUGHS)
You're funny, Alfred.
I honestly haven't
laughed this much
in a very long time.
I'm glad I'm able to
amuse you, Ms. Gale.
- Your accent, I love it.
- (DOG BARKING)
Where are you from?
A charming place called
Whitechapel in East End, London.
Go back often?
No.
Sadly, no.
Well, perhaps, you should.
Why did you leave?
Well, I was in the military.
I was really proud
to serve my country,
not so proud of
some of the things
we had to do, though.
And when I left, I
found myself, um, lost.
You know, it was
a tough transition.
Then I met this man
who changed my life.
He brought me to
America, gave me a job.
And where is that man now?
He's dead.
And I miss him.
I miss him very much.
(VEHICLE ARRIVING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Who's that, your boyfriend?
MAN: Hey, you
didn't call me back.
I was heading to the
diner to pick you up.
Oh, that wasn't necessary.
Alfred was kind enough
to walk me home.
Thank you, sir.
I hate to think of Tiff alone
on these streets after dark.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Drop the act, sunshine.
I've seen her face!
It was your idea, was it?
Wear her hair down
and cover the bruising?
Oh, my. What a little
tattletale she's been.
- What am I to do with her?
- TIFFANY: Stop it!
Don't make things
worse. I can handle it.
Listen to me!
Listen! Listen to me!
You stay away from him.
He's dangerous. Let
me walk you home.
I'll be fine.
MAN: Oh, Tiffany, what did I tell
you about talking to strange men?
It's time to go. We
have so much to discuss.
You be careful.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(DOG YELPS)
There was a fatality
at the bomb site.
A young man found in a room
below the impact site and...
- Well, perhaps I should just show you.
- Of course.
Yeah. (CLEARS THROAT)
The cause of death
was ingested poison.
Now, see the discoloration
around the mouth?
LUCIUS: The poison entered
directly into the bloodstream?
But see, that's
not what's unusual.
There seems to be something
emanating from
within the victim's body.
Time of death was
several hours ago,
but this foreign,
organic material
is not only alive but growing.
LUCIUS: Seems like moss.
CORONER: Toxicodendron radicans.
Poison ivy?
Yes, and microscopic at
first but multiplying, growing.
Living off the
victim's dead tissue.
Fascinating.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
BARBARA: So the
commercial worked.
We're back and busier than ever.
Good, 'cause
that's the last time
you're getting me on camera.
Who's that?
BARBARA: Who's who?
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (BARBARA SIGHS)
Selina, will you tell
those brats over there
to keep it down?
SELINA: Why me?
Because you're a partner now,
and also, the one
paying is a friend of yours.
Bruce.
What's up?
Champagne?
- No.
- Why?
They don't card you
here, and even if they did,
this is Gotham.
By "they" you mean me.
This is my place, too.
- Really?
- Yeah.
So you wanna tell
your little brat pack here
to reel it in a little, or
should I call your keeper?
Go ahead, call Alfred,
he won't answer.
Why?
'Cause I fired him.
It was time to move on,
you know what I'm saying?
(SCOFFS)
You sure about that?
- I'm not buying it.
- Not buying what?
This.
You.
Firing Alfred. What
are you trying to prove?
MAN 1: I saw her first. MAN 2:
The lady was speaking with me.
(MEN GRUNTING)
Hey, hey.
(MAN GROANS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Silly boys.
I'm really not sure
what got into them.
You should leave.
Well, that's awfully rude.
But you always were.
Who is that woman?
She seems to know you.
Who cares?
Redheads, they're
all crazy, am I right?
Ivy.
I like what you've
done with the place.
Thank you. Though, it
was hardly a challenge
after what that crazy
bird passed for as taste.
What brings you here, my love?
Actually, you know,
I'm so proud to say that
I seem to maintain a very good
relationship with all my exes.
- You...
- Leave me off that list.
Hmm. What can I
do you for, Jimmy?
The Doc? You know him?
Oh.
The Doc.
I believe he was the target
of an assassination attempt
in The Narrows this morning.
Do you now? And you
want to protect the Doc?
I wanna know who
wanted to kill him and why.
You know him or not?
Oh, I know the Doc.
Dangerous character.
Someone like that,
you might wanna shoot
first then ask questions later.
Something you're good at.
- Where is he?
- With Ed Nygma.
They're partners.
- Where?
- The Narrows.
Place called Cherry's.
Careful, Jim.
Sometimes we search for
things we don't wish to find.
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Harper, what's up?
HARPER: I'm at a murder
scene in The Narrows.
I'm busy, can you handle it?
You're gonna wanna
check this out in person.
I have the suspect in custody.
Alfred Pennyworth.
(HANGS UP)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
HARPER: Beaten to death.
Local girl.
Garbage collectors found
her about an hour ago,
she lived with her boyfriend
who was at work all night.
He told us that him
and Pennyworth
got into it earlier.
Says that he was
trying to keep him
separate from his girlfriend,
says that he made
advances towards the victim.
According to him,
Pennyworth got rough.
Rough? That doesn't
sound like him.
Come on, you and
I both have seen
Alfred lose his temper.
There's more.
This was found next to the body.
It's an SAS signet ring.
Impressions of it are
on the victim's face.
My God.
Thanks.
Give us a minute.
Is this yours?
- Yes, but I...
- You hit this girl?
No.
How could you even ask
that? It was the boyfriend.
I mean, he's beat her before,
now he's gone and
bloody killed her.
He says you were
fighting with him.
Because he beat her!
I swear, he's a liar.
All right, calm down.
You're in enough
trouble as it is.
The last thing you need
to do is lose your temper.
Who was this girl to you?
She was a friend.
Just a friend.
What, you just met her?
Well, I know you find this
hard to believe, Gordon,
but we connected.
She was a beautiful, kind soul.
Her murderer's
name is Rooney, right,
- Gil Rooney.
- He has an alibi.
I swear to God, I'm gonna
kill that son of a bitch!
Calm down.
Take a breath.
Go with Harper to the precinct,
make a statement.
I'll find you later, yeah?
And you're gonna arrest
Rooney as well, yeah?
- He will make a statement, yes.
- HARPER: Cap.
Got a witness who saw
Pennyworth and the
boyfriend getting into it.
- She saw the whole thing.
- GORDON: All right.
Take Alfred back
to the precinct.
I'll come by after my last stop.
Okay, where is he?
Damn it.
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
Tabitha.
Butch?
Oh, my God, it worked.
It hurt, I'll tell you that.
What happened to you?
And who turned
you into this thing?
BUTCH: I don't remember much.
I remember Barbara
shooting me in the head.
Something in that
swamp brought me back.
I'm a monster.
(SIGHS)
I came here...
Butch, tell me.
I came here
because the one thing
that's still very clear
in this thick head of mine
is my feelings for you.
I still love you, Tabby.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
Goodbye, Tabby.
- Thank you for waiting.
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
It's worth it, you'll see.
Believe in her passion,
and your champion, she'll be.
Bombs can't stop
her, nor bullets, too.
'Cause she's here to
speak out and fight for you.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Ready to battle,
ready to rock.
People of The Narrows,
here's the Doc.
(CROWD CHEERING)
CROWD: (CHANTING) Doc, Doc, Doc.
Doc, Doc, Doc.
This morning,
someone tried to kill me.
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
Maybe it was someone
from the outside,
maybe it was one of you.
CROWD: No, no way.
LEE: You know what? I
don't know. And I don't care.
But what I do know
is that someone did not
like what I was saying.
Now why would the
idea of a united Narrows
scare people?
I'll tell you why.
Because a united Narrows
is a strong Narrows.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Guess what?
They should be scared.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Magnificent, isn't she?
- It's been forever, right?
- I should bust you, right now.
Oh, come on, Jim, don't be
grumpy. Your ex has my full support.
She's really gonna
change things around here.
Someone hired Griffin
Krank to kill her this morning.
You really think they
won't do it again?
Krank?
A toy maker but
also an assassin.
(CHUCKLES)
That is so Gotham.
Because together we have
the power to change our lives.
CROWD: Yeah! MAN: That's right.
LEE: Imagine a
hospital, imagine schools.
Imagine these slums torn down.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Your children deserve better.
Your children deserve life!
(CHEERING)
Yeah!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Jim.
Doc.
I like to think of that
as a sign of respect,
not just a lack of imagination.
How long you been back?
A while.
I wish you would
have contacted me.
I've been busy.
I can see that.
You look great.
You look the same.
Are you here to arrest someone?
- Me?
- (NYGMA CHUCKLES)
I'm here because
someone wants you dead.
The assassin's
still on the loose,
as is the person who
hired him. You're not safe.
It's Gotham, is
anyone ever safe?
So, you're partners
with Ed, huh?
Why?
I'm right here.
Why not?
Wouldn't have
been my first choice,
but the universe has funny ways.
Still here.
I'll see you around, Jim.
I'm gonna take a look around.
That's...
Oh, boy.
I've been trying to get to you.
(PANTING)
You shouldn't be here,
you're a wanted man.
Better stay cool on
me. I've got friends...
- (GROANS)
- That was for Tiffany.
(GROANS)
- And that was for me.
- Help me!
This man killed my
girlfriend. He's a maniac.
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- (GROANS)
You're making this too easy.
I'll just tell the cops
this was self-defense.
(MEN GROANING)
Sorry, it took me so
long, I was in the john.
I liked you better when
you were making tea.
(PANTING)
Harvey,
what the bloody hell
are you doing here?
I work here.
Don't say it like that,
this place has history.
I love bartending, it involves
two of my favorite things,
- drinking and ignoring people.
- (CHUCKLES)
Who are these jokers?
Oh, he's a bloody murderer.
Then call a cop,
I'm a bartender.
No, he's the murderer.
- I have an alibi.
- HARVEY: Oh! Yeah?
Let me guess, one of
these guys is your alibi?
- What do you say now, pal?
- Oh, I'm not an alibi.
I'll call it in.
(CREAKING)
IVY: Hi, kitty-cat.
You suck at following
people, by the way.
Ivy?
In the flesh.
Just different flesh.
What happened to you?
(SCOFFS)
Something wonderful.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
Can you feel that?
Coursing through your veins,
it's my essence.
Is your head swimming?
Your mouth drying up?
It lives within me now.
This power.
(GROANING)
Drink.
It'll counteract the toxin.
It took me a few tries,
but it'll work.
(COUGHS)
See?
(SELINA PANTING)
You have to trust me.
You've gone crazy.
No, I haven't.
I've been reborn.
And I will never
be underestimated
or ignored ever again.
You always looked
after me, Selina.
Now, let me help you.
Let's make Gotham our bitch.
Please, don't hurt me.
Why would I do that?
You tried to kill Lee.
Yeah, because you paid me to.
What?
You paid me good
money to kill the Doc.
Used your alias, the Riddler.
(LAUGHING)
You want me to
finish the job or not?
I came to you?
Paid in cash.
Said the Doc was
holding you back,
she has to die, or
you can't be free.
Oh, God.
I put myself at
great risk for you.
Cops came to my workshop,
I can't go back there.
- My son...
- Let go of him!
Get down, Ed!
What the hell were you
thinking, going after him alone?
Well, clearly I wasn't thinking.
(NYGMA EXHALES)
Damn it.
Did he say anything
about who hired him?
(STAMMERS) It was him, all him.
He was a lone wolf.
That's what he said.
He was afraid of what Lee
was gonna do to The Narrows.
Are you sure? His son said
he was talking to somebody
on the phone about the Doc.
(STAMMERS) He said
that he was calling around
trying to get support, but
no one would help him.
So he went alone. Crazy.
Crazy loon.
He told you all that?
Honestly, I'm not
much of a threat.
I'm so lucky that you
came out here, Jim,
I don't know what
I would have done.
This is Captain Gordon.
I have a suspect down,
outside Cherry's place,
on State Street, in The Narrows.
Send all available units.
Nice job, Ed, I guess.
I'm back. (LAUGHS)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
OFFICER: Move.
HARVEY: Of all the
beer halls in the city, huh?
Who was it that
that jerk killed?
(DOOR CLOSES)
A lady.
Very beautiful.
Kind, nice lady.
Then I drink to her.
(DOOR OPENS)
Heard the call on the radio.
Don't worry, we'll
get him to talk.
How you been?
Awesome.
I've missed you.
Is that so?
Well, I haven't missed you.
I haven't missed begging
you not to do something
just to watch you go
ahead and do it anyway.
Haven't missed watching
you bang Falcone's daughter,
while she uses you
to get rid of Penguin.
Something's eating at you, Jim.
I don't know what it is,
but you're no good
at keeping secrets.
And you're not gonna feel
clean till you get it off your chest.
You didn't come down here
because you miss me as a cop.
You came here to confess.
You want me to be your
priest. Well, sorry, pal.
I'm not interested.
So hit the bricks,
take that with you.
English - SDH